A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Issue Books, Series 17 FA363
Rockefeller Archive Center
- First Gubernatorial Term, 1958-1962; 2; 5.4 Cubic Feet
  - Volume 33 - Transportation and Highways, 1958-1962 (Box 36, Folder 201)
    Tab 28 Legislation -- An Act, To provide state assistance to certain tax districts in respect of reductions in real property taxes on the intangible portion of special franchise property of railroads, and making an appropriation therefor, March 25, 1959.
    Tab 29 NAR Statement -- announcement of appointment by Governor Rockefeller of a committee to consider problems related to the reconstruction of Westchester County parkway system, March 31, 1959.
    Tab 30 Press Release, April 11, 1959 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Int. 1718, Pr. 1726, on the Brooklyn approach to the proposed Narrows Bridge, April 8, 1959.
    Tab 31 Transcript -- text of Statewide telecast by NAR over WCBS-TV, April 15, 1959.
    Tab 32 Press Release, April 24, 1959 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Int. 188, Pr. 4236, relaxing the load requirements of vehicles, April 22, 1959.
    Tab 33 Press Release, April 24, 1959 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Int. 35534, Pr. 3669, permitting interstate agreements for tax relief to common carriers, April 24, 1959.
    Tab 34 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1959 -- Chapters 16, 636, 636, 638-639, 640-641, 420, 588, 203; Joint Res. 134, Sen. Print 1528.
    Tab 35 NAR Statement -- address by Governor Rockefeller to Jefferson County Republican Committee on aviation transportation, reports on Port Development and North-South Expressway, July 18, 1959.
    Tab 36 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller on resumption of federal aid highway construction, September 9, 1959.
    Tab 37 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller and Progress Report, on the State's Program on railroad and commuter problems, September 29, 1959.
    Tab 38 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller supporting Amendment #6 permitting transfer of Barge Canal to Federal Government, November 1, 1959.
    Tab 39 Summary of Special Studies on Transportation and Port Development and Westchester Parkway System (Leg. Research Rept.) -- November 11, 1959.
  - Volume 34 - Transportation and Highways, 1958-1962 (Box 36, Folder 202)
    Tab 41 Report -- Report of Governor' Committee on Westchester County Parkway System, January 15, 1960 (Release January 18, 1960).
    Tab 42 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1960 -- Chapter 917, 1071; 1960-1961 Executive Budget; Chapter 692, 649, 1037, 334, 315.
    Tab 43 NAR Statement -- address by Governor Rockefeller on Northway Section Opening, Plattsburgh, October 24, 1960.
    Tab 44 NAR Statement -- statement on meeting of Governor Rockefeller, Abraham Ribicoff, Mayor Wagner and County Executive Michaelian on 8-Point Program for New Haven Railroad, October 25, 1960.
    Tab 45 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller on accelerated construction of State highways, November 1, 1960.
    Tab 46 NAR Statement -- address by Governor Rockefeller at New York State Chapter of Associated General Contractors of America, on "Highway Construction and Economic Growth," Kiamesha Lake, December 7, 1960.
    Tab 47 NAR Statement -- statement on meeting of Interstate Staff Committee on New Haven Railroad, December 7, 1960.
    Tab 48 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller and The New York Central Railroad's participation in the State Commuter Car Program, December 15, 1960.
    Tab 49 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 4, 1961.
    Tab 50 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of bids for three highway construction projects in labor surplus areas, January 18, 1961.
    Tab 51 NAR Statement -- excerpts from address by Governor Rockefeller at Niagara Falls Chamber of Commerce, on proposed highway projects in the Niagara Frontier, February 9, 1961.
    Tab 52 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor's Press Secretary, concerning President Kennedy's request to speed public works as an anti-recession measure, February 17, 1961.
    Tab 53 Correspondence -- letter from Governor Rockefeller to President Kennedy requesting authorization for the States to draw on their federal highway fund allocations, March 5, 1961.
    Tab 54 NAR Statement -- Special Message by Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature on program to assist commuter railroads, March 7, 1961.
    Tab 55 Correspondence -- letter by Governor Rockefeller for presentation at House Ways and Means Committee Hearing on the Federal Interstate Highway System, urging restoration of the Interstate Highway program, March 15, 1961.
    Tab 56 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of $100 million appropriation to accelerate Federal-State highway construction to stimulate economy, March 24, 1961.
    Tab 57 Press Release, April 15, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 935, which would impede highway program by increasing State's costs for arterial highways, April 11, 1961.
    Tab 58 NAR Statement -- address by Governor Rockefeller at Suffolk County Republican Dinner, on $43.4 million highway program for Suffolk County, Huntington, April 13, 1961.
    Tab 59 Press Release, April 22, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 3892 and Senate Bill Int. 2208, designating two new arterial routes in Niagara Falls, April 178, 1961.
    Tab 60 Press Release, April 22, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 3380, Pr. 3510, designating a new arterial route in Tonawanda, April 17, 1961.
    Tab 61 Press Release, April 22, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 3526, Pr. 3878, relocating a portion of the proposed Southern Expressway in Erie County, April 17, 1961.
    Tab 62 Press Release, April 22, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 4254, Pr. 5235, providing for the Gowanda Expressway in the western part of Erie County, April 17, 1961.
    Tab 63 Press Release, April 22, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 926, Pr. 2795, authorizing a new section of State highway in Port Chester, April 17, 1961.
    Tab 64 Press Release, April 22, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 1539, Pr. 1580, providing that upon relocation of a section of State Highway 657 in Westchester County, the old section shall be maintained by the State, April 17, 1961.
    Tab 65 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 2955, Pr. 3158, authorizing construction of a major highway across the northernmost counties of the State, April 24, 1961.
    Tab 66 Press Release, April 22, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 3989, Pr. 4189, authorizing a new arterial highway along the shore of Staten Island, April 24, 1961.
    Tab 67 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1961 -- Chapters 199, 200, 201, Senate Bill Int. 513, Chapters 312, 273, 274, Senate Resolution 31, Chapters 316, 79, 958, 478.
    Tab 68 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of highway construction for 1964-1965 New York World's Fair, April 26, 1961.
    Tab 69 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of $8 million State contract for 53 air conditioned coaches for New York Central Railroad, May 24, 1961.
    Tab 70 NAR Statement -- address by Governor Rockefeller at dedication of Glens Falls Bypass Section of the Northway, on State's highway program, May 26, 1961.
    Tab 71 NAR Statement -- statement concerning highway program as second major State function, May 31, 1961.
    Tab 72 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of more than $3 million in additional State highway contracts in Rockland County, June 12, 1961.
    Tab 73 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller that New York State is eligible for $2 million federal bonus for controlling advertising on interstate highways, June 15, 1961.
    Tab 74 NAR Statement -- statement of intervention of New York State before Interstate Commerce Commission on the proposed merger of eastern railroads, June 19, 1961.
    Tab 75 NAR Statement -- announcement of $2.3 million highway project in town of Salina, north of Syracuse, July 7, 1961.
  - Volume 34 - Transportation and Highways, 1958-1962 (Box 36, Folder 203)
    Tab 76 Correspondence -- correspondence with New York State Thruway Authority, on construction of Second North Grand Island Bridge with Thruway moneys, July 13, 1961.
    Tab 77 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of proposed Collier St.-Brandywine Arterial Highway in Binghamton, July 16, 1961.
    Tab 78 NAR Statement -- excerpt from address by Governor Rockefeller to Annual American Municipal Congress, on New York State program to aid commuter transportation, Seattle, August 28, 1951.
    Tab 79 NAR Statement -- announcement of appointment of Tri-State Transportation Committee to study transportation problems in metropolitan area of New York, New Jersey and Connecticut, August 30, 1961.
    Tab 80 NAR Statement -- statement concerning New York State officials attending Interstate Commerce Commission hearings on proposed merger of eastern railroads, September10, 1961.
    Tab 81 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller to the Interstate Commerce Commission, on application for control of the Baltimore & Ohio Railroad, Washington, September 11, 1961.
    Tab 82 NAR Statement -- excerpt from address by Governor Rockefeller at Cornell University, on the proposed $4.3 million Ithaca Northeast Arterial, Ithaca, September 12, 1961.
    Tab 83 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller on State's advance of $2.1 million to Rochester for arterial highway, September 13, 1961.
    Tab 84 NAR Statement -- announcement of meeting of the Tri-State Transportation Committee with federal officials for purposes of orientation, September 18, 1961.
    Tab 85 NAR Statement -- announcement of appointment of local government cooperating committees in New York, New Jersey and Connecticut to work with Tri-State Transportation Committee, September 28, 1961.
    Tab 86 NAR Statement -- excerpts from address by Governor Rockefeller at University of Buffalo, on Federal and State railroad program, September 29, 1961.
    Tab 87 NAR Statement -- address by Governor Rockefeller at National Conference of State Legislative Leaders, on necessary State and Federal measures to resolve transportation problems, Nevada, October 5, 1961.
    Tab 88 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of construction of sections of North-South Expressway and Interstate Route 81 in Syracuse, October 11, 1961.
    Tab 89 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of construction of major sections of Route 26 and Route 17 in Broome and Delaware Counties, November 14, 1961.
    Tab 90 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of independent study on costs of transportation services of New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad, December 6, 1961.
    Tab 91 NAR Statement -- statement on State's accelerated highway development, December 7, 1961.
    Tab 92 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller on State's accelerated highway development, December 10, 1961.
    Tab 93 NAR Statement -- announcement of meetings of the Tri-State Transportation Committee with local cooperating committees, December 11, 1961.
    Tab 94 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 3, 1962.
    Tab 95 NAR Statement -- announcement of proposed meeting among Governor Rockefeller, Governors of Connecticut, Massachusetts, and Rhode Island, Mayor Wagner and Westchester County Executive, to discuss New Haven Railroad, January 5, 1962.
    Tab 96 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of proposed construction of North-South Expressway in Cortland County, February 1, 1962.
    Tab 97 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of request to the Federal Government to include segment of Southern Tier Expressway in the Interstate System, February 2, 1962.
    Tab 98 Correspondence -- letter from Secretary to Governor Rockefeller, to Deputy Special Council to the President, on measures to solve the New Haven Railroad problem, February 16, 1962.
    Tab 99 Correspondence -- letter from Governor Rockefeller to State Senator Bush, reviewing action taken by the State to resolve the New Haven Railroad problem, March 6, 1962.
    Tab 100 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller, announcing proposed legislative action to cope with Fifth Avenue Coach Line strike in New York City, March 11, 1962. (see also "State-Local Relations").
    Tab 101 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of delivery under the State program of the first 53 commuter cars to the New York Central Railroad, March 21, 1962.
    Tab 102 NAR Statement -- statement on Governor Rockefeller's approval of legislation authorizing Port Authority to rehabilitate the Hudson and Manhattan Railroad, March 27, 1962.
    Tab 103 Press Release, April 24, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill Int. 4821, Pr. 5115, designating a proposed new "Interstate highway" across the northern part of the State, April 4, 1962.
    Tab 104 Press Release, May 1, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bills, Int. 4418, Int. 4419, designating two new State arterial highways in Niagara Falls, April 19, 1962.
    Tab 105 Press Release, May 1, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 4472, Pr. 4719, permitting municipalities to render financial assistance to commuter railroads, April 29, 1962.
    Tab 106 Press Release, May 1, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 3203, Pr. 3284, retaining in the State Highway System a 7-mile section of Route 9 in Westchester County, April 30, 1962.
    Tab 107 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1962 -- Senate Resolution 47, Chapters 264, 319, 288, 209, 525, 878, 511, 258, 840, 729, 730.
    Tab 108 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller that Port of New York Authority will purchase 30 new commuter cars for lease to Long Island Railroad, May 15, 1962.
    Tab 109 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of arterial highway project for Schenectady, May 24, 1962.
    Tab 110 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of $12 million arterial highway system for Troy, May 25, 1962.
    Tab 111 NAR Statement -- address by Governor Rockefeller at Governors' Conference calling for a national policy on transportation and creation of a Department of Transportation, Hershey, Pennsylvania, July 3, 1962.
    Tab 112 Correspondence -- letter from Governor Rockefeller to federal agencies, requesting financial assistance for Tri-State Transportation Committee, July 9, 1962.
    Tab 113 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of immediate study of Long Island Railroad, July 19, 1962.
    Tab 114 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of a study of the feasibility of establishing a high-speed ferry system across Long Island Sound, July 19, 1962.
    Tab 115 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of 30 new air-conditioned cars for the Long Island Railroad, August 9, 1962.
    Tab 116 Correspondence -- letter from Governor Rockefeller to Secretary of Commerce Hodges, urging passage of federal highway act to expedite state highway construction, August 27, 1962.
    Tab 117 NAR Statement -- address by Governor Rockefeller at dedication of George Washington Bridge, on federal-state highway projects, New York City, August 29, 1962.